all right we are live welcome to the
project round table in this session
we're going to be as representing our
various projects if we have one and if
not then we can just chime in on other
people's projects as required I think
we're in theory waiting on one other
person to really get going but I guess
we could probably start with
introductions and whatnot you know how
about you and I go first just because
our viewers are more used to us say in
ours and then it just cuz if Bentley's
coming I don't know if he was like then
he'll hear Brad's and Susan who becomes
suppose to ours which are you know maybe
the usual and then also Brad and Susan
can see you how it is we do it right
that makes sense um well what were the
actual steps that we took it yes like
who you are what your project is a brief
description of your project we maybe
don't need to do that but we'll do it at
this time and and then what you've been
up to and since your last meeting what
you're taking on if you want to share
that and what you could use help with so
you don't need to necessarily answer all
those but that that general what many of
her pieces are then yes as I'm a drill
the project is wiki election it is a
platform to help fight misinformation in
politics science and news since the last
time I have been busy on working on the
specs just the sort of early draft
possibly give to a developer to actually
start coding the early versions of the
platform
what helpful need will end up being I'll
be hiring a developer oh and as well I
do bi-weekly live streams not not not
today but a week from today on Saturdays
at noon pacific and i'm looking for more
people to I guess be panelists or be
guest hosts or whatever you want to call
it to sort of you know see the
presentation ask questions as it goes
and actually sort of be a
you know a guess and a sounding board
for ways to improve the ideas go
hopefully that meant its thank you I am
Jubilee my project by current project in
solution raisins which is a structured
hour-long generative conversation where
at the end we have a actual solution
that we could implement now if we had
10,000 people at 100 simply Osley breads
all right we have so solutions at that
what did i do last week i had online
what is your sis if you want to just
brad go out completely and then come
back and I don't know there's some weird
sound on your and there we go and follow
it back in so he was I was trying to
type with him before
um what is it we do so last week we had
our first live project raising on
Wednesday we did it on mental health and
emotional health
weirdly although he did it kind of with
the idea of kovat 19 it was the one that
Cove in nineteen KITT probably came up
with in the least I think because we
have so many issues with it just
normally in mental health we did this is
showing that anyway not point of this is
this conversation and so did that I'm
looking to do that live every Wednesday
have a different solution or easy answer
in your live green session and I have
Suzie and then so this week I'm figuring
out what the topic is for this Wednesday
both them are a little more calm a
little more convoluted to explain that
have been offered as suggestions rather
than just like transportation education
and so figure you know the wording and
how we have that conversation and I
don't know exactly what I could use help
with at the moment I think things are
just unfolding in their in their proper
time if anyone would like to join this
Wednesday that is what we can always use
more Wednesdays at 8:30 in the morning
Pacific time we're having a conversation
that generates
that is ocean racing this week so Susan
if you would like to go or Brad you want
to Susan you might buy go ahead brown
someone else on my window stop
temporarily so going to be quick so I'm
Brad I am starting a regenerative
agriculture venture in Columbus Ohio
it's in a urban environment or house is
located on one acre so we're trying to
utilize three-quarters of an acre to
grow as much as we can using bio
intensive methods permaculture methods
and a little bit from the market
gardener style type of production line
currently is the first year so we're
just starting growing things but as far
as health we are gonna try to open
source solutions on packaging I'm trying
to get a packaging that is compostable
and that I could be able to 3d print or
grow as my Sicilian molds but I don't
have the details that ironed out yet so
hopefully some people from the game
begin the or people on the Internet can
help me crowd source some solutions for
that all right thank you
welcome Mathias is that your how do you
see your name much Mateus
that's my inflatable claim so perfect
nice to see you at jump in and you can
see a Susan's about to share and you can
see how it goes your since you've seen
our project if you have one what what
that project is and what you've been
doing what you will be doing and what
you could use help on if you have you
don't need to share all of that but any
of that or you can pass and just have a
conversation other people's projects
okay so I started project two weeks ago
three weeks ago called B Connect which
was the small website to connect to
schedule meetings
and you know mm-hmm
try to organize some adult meetings
whenever they are needed in these times
and for the past weeks it's been like um
hope I hope to get back to it next week
if possible to bring it to more usable
shape put the coat on it hop and see if
it's often used to anyone and yeah
that's basically a bit okay thank you
Susan if you want to share sorry yes
thank you so the project that I've been
working on for the last year or so is a
two role flow cultural Commons and it's
an emerging space for settlers and First
Peoples to have or to make sense of the
of our treaty agreements so what I
worked on last week actually am
attending an online course with the
buckminster fuller Institute and we've
been going through a series of speakers
and then activities so we had Tom she I
think a couple weeks back and he talked
about rapid prototyping so even though
I've sort of been doing that all along I
decided I would do more of it so I did a
couple more things for the site but
actually it was last weekend I think I
attended another event online with the
rebel wisdom or group and it was an
all-day event and at the end we did this
really interesting thing called the
offers and needs market so I don't know
if anyone's heard of that but I was
really excited about it because that is
one of the things that I wanted to
create one of the components or the
modules for the Commons is some sort of
time bank sharing of skills thing so
they actually did it but they did it on
a spreadsheet so it was like cool and it
happened within a full hour of course
there was a lot of people attending so
that helped so I decided to do that
myself
so what I did is I created a sort of
used that template
as my template for with a spreadsheet
that I set up and then I created a page
on my website and then I created a page
on Facebook for the first time and then
I just started I invited people that I
knew and also promoted it on Twitter so
yeah what I need help with is if anyone
wants to help me do the aux test on it
give me some feedback as to whether or
not they think that the process makes
sense and and any help on the idea of
offers and needs markets virtually I've
heard a lot of people say oh it really
works well and you're doing it in person
I did see it work well online but there
was a whole bunch of people there was
like 65 people doing that at the same
time so you know doesn't work when you
just dribs and drabs people are just
coming in very slowly anyhow so yeah I'd
appreciate feedback on that thank you
all right thank you this is only the
we've done a few of these with other
people joining it was the first time
that we've had as many people and I
totally forgot to take notes on what
everyone's ask is it everyone reiterate
what they would like to get out of this
noise and other things going on if you
don't mind I'm just I'm reading
everybody a crowd noise and you're not
talking okay I don't have any need at
this at this point when it's when I
called it's more usable it would be nice
to get some people to actually test it
and see if yeah it's useful you know and
to improve the UX prompt and yeah some
feedback generally got a question or
were you the one who did it was is it a
it's like one sheet and it's about
scheduling like a conversation that
gives me know if there's two different
things it's like one's yours is it cool
I didn't briefly look at it but I have
yet
use it or in budget I liked the idea was
made though yeah it was ad hoc like
impulse coming because there is this
idea and I thought okay let's see how
long it would take to actually write it
so I might start though at the current
state it needs some improvement so I and
my project was for he election the
things that I wouldn't help with would
be I mean it's kind of an open one but
anything to do with marketing or sort of
explaining the the product and I could
probably use help with and then a lot
more sort of definitely need help in the
near future basis we need to work with a
developer to actually build a prototype
and then as well anybody who's
interested in discussing the topic of
misinformation in either news science or
politics took to attendee livestream on
the given day just to discuss that topic
and get feedback that kind of thing
thank you I'm just gonna go mute my kid
once I get so was oh can I hear you can
you hear me Adrian yep so I wanted to
ask what type of developer like what
language what do you what's the platform
what's the stack what do you do that I'm
not sure yet
I don't really I mean okay it's going to
be some sort of database driven web
application okay
aside from that I mean I assume probably
MS sequel for the database and then I'm
not thinking about the the front-end
that there there should probably would
be a conversation before the coding
actually starts about what the
environment is and you know why you
choose one language over another
but if there is it sort of a direct
reach I'll probably just end up going
through upwork and then that will be a
part of you know people's sort of quotes
is here someone it'll cost and here's D
languages that I would did develop it in
like at least pinged those ideas off of
a few developers I know but just don't
have time to work on a full project are
you hard coding the whole thing are you
working from some sort of content
management system
um there's already prototypes built in
in knack so there's already sort of some
basic ones online and then the next
version of will be hard-coded so what
snack what snack a Mac is kind of a roll
your own like basic database-driven
web portal type software it's the one
that I used to build the together tech
rotor type that I'll be sharing in the
game be project channel probably today
to start sort of kidding since its
feedback where it has a bit of the event
booking it has a bit of an offers
actually doesn't have it offers market
yet but it does have any needs list
where where projects can say what they
need help what and do people can see it
but I do like the idea of adding and
offers one so I'm they do that after but
it's like if you've ever used Salesforce
it's like a really basic version of
Salesforce where you can sort of add
your own tables and then you know build
your layouts and there's like a public
version and then you a person where you
can actually have members create users
and login and interact that way is that
NAC nak KN AZ ah sorry Kay and ACK okay
like you know I've got okay thank you
it's one of the few apps that's actually
spelled like a real word you know yeah
silence Susan I just want to know if you
have you watched oh no I don't want you
to autoplay have you watched the TED
talk or heard of Barbara
you know she has a TED talk which I
really enjoy
it's kind of in the app what you
adventure the offers and needs she
doesn't in person but I know she's
working on doing a web-based application
that is the same thing online I don't
know what that is currently what state
it's currently in but she is his TED
talk where she talks about wish and
obstacle or she'll have a big group of
people in the audience and you'll have
someone stand up and say you know I wish
I could go on a cruise but I don't have
childcare and generally speaking
somebody else is like actually my kid
might you know my sublet needs someone
to stay with I'd be like questioning
that example because I'm like just some
random son comes and stays and watches
your kid needed a dog sitter let's say
than someone someone comes and stays in
their house and someone else just want
to cruise tickets and they give it to
them that these things end up happening
but you do have to kind of have a group
together in order for those things to
happen and that's kind of the more
timely based one but I would just
suggest watching the TED talk I can send
it to you if you want so that was very
hard it's just maybe it'll be
inspirational it's kind of I always
enjoyed watching that one wanted to
create the technology to do that online
to be like yes how do we create that I
like the rubber wisdom is is doing that
that is the stuff the principle wisdom
does generally you have to be a paid
subscriber right yeah but they they they
open it up for free
for some reason like seven hours for
free so it was like awesome it was about
sense making an embodiment so Jamie
wheel was the keynote speaker and then
there was a lot of actual real
activities breathing activities even
yoga and so on to participate in yeah
pretty neat yeah I think that having any
kind of service like that online that
there's enough people on is I mean we're
kind of seeing him cope at 19 we're seen
and telehealth and things where it's
very structured it's like here's the
offer here's the want for food and
Medicaid
and things that are that are dire but I
there's a vast market for that
everyone has needs and everyone has
something to give and if we can match
those up in any way and that is game
beating well I think there's a vast
market for this too but again it comes
down to trust whether or not you're
gonna trust to actually go post your
offers and needs right there's a whole
psychological component you know you're
gonna expose you know who knows it's
what people think when they see when
they see those two words is are those
the right two words is that a good name
for it and I guess ran with what was
there yeah so I do like wish and
obstacle because it's very it's like
offer and once are more specific and to
me it does somewhat have a charity basis
to it where it's like oh I have food to
offer but of course I'm what I'm
implying is I'm offering that food to
people who don't have it right as
opposed to hey can you use it which is a
different it's more peer-to-peer right
now during this time crisis I understand
we need to feed the hungry so that's a
different dynamic but a obstacle which
is like everybody has wishes and
everybody has obstacles as to why you're
doing it and the whole point is we're
each other solution to those obstacles
right like whether it's an internal one
or an external one someone else is much
generally there it's easier for them to
find a solution to your obstacle than
their own obstacle and this is it like
any 100 people getting together in a
room and doing this process they have
solution to each other's obstacles in
real concrete ways like oh I just want
to get to a cruise and you wanted to go
on a cruise I'm not gonna go here have
them you know someone like their
examples in it are amazing just someone
I think wanted a horse ranch someone's
like all my parents are retiring they
want they're looking for someone to take
it over and like just weird things like
that that just the right person shows up
at the right time and that showcases
itself but how to do that online with
the trust with is is part of what I
think she is she's doing I don't have a
warm contact with her like I don't have
I don't know but I have a second this
woman who pops into my periscope sever
it was so frequently every so often and
she is amazing her name is angel
and she's given me so much edition
anyway she knows this other person
Barbara and in sorry you said sheer sh e
er SH er I believe not the TED talks
called isolation is the dream killer not
your attitude
Barbara shear okay go ahead ex prog talk
big side it's a good one put it see what
that that lease here also
Brad it's at Brad's mic and camera I'm
working so I told him to restart his
computer but he may or may not be back
and if he comes back we have a full
house which doesn't happen very often
that's right Bentley your Excuse you're
just at home like everyone right nothing
better to do would you like to do your
what you've been up to you and what your
thing is we've all we've all dinners
sure so I've done I spent about another
30 35 hours on the project on my project
last week which is great I have a a user
that's going to put it on a demo site in
the next week or so so that'll be good
I've started debate on a pit bull ban in
Denver so I'm starting to fill that out
as one of the first sample debates so a
lot is happening so I guess that's my
update though is there anything you'd
like help with someone magically has to
help really what I'm looking for is
someone who's Pro keeping a ban in
Denver the people been in Denver it's
hard to find so I there's several of
them on the internet it might just have
to reach out to them but if y'all know
of anybody that might that I do that
that might be helpful but nothing else
up there I know anyone but does it need
to be a pro person in Denver or can it
just be a pro person no yeah just
someone who would be
to do research and look up stuff and I
find it people are most capable of doing
that when they actually believe in the
side that they're doing it'd be nice if
we could all be completely rational and
our lawyer yeah so yeah that so that
yeah just just as long as they would
they think that
a breed-specific ban is not the worst
thing in the world so yeah we need some
like know what they're called like when
you're on a date you bring like cards
they're like what's your favorite color
what's your favorite like topic
generators for when although we did have
some asks and we're just kind of talking
about them Adriel how do you think we
can get you guests for your with the
election I don't think having the same
person constantly I mean I'm happy to do
a week but I don't like happy um part of
what I'm hoping will do it as I've also
got the prototype that I'm hoping to
sort of get to a usable state and share
with the game be projects group
hopefully tit today knows
and once that's online then part of that
is for for projects to sort of be able
to say hey here's what we help with and
there is sort of that events scheduling
tool where it does both kind of events
it does events that projects are hosting
manages does general discussions that
sort of a have like a minimum threshold
in order to actually happen if that
makes sense
so part of it is I'm hoping to build up
that tool and then just being able to
post it there and then then that shifts
it to trying to get people to use that
tool so they can go there and see what
all the projects you need help with and
then hoping that somebody says oh that
sounds neat and and contacts all right
so they're already get interviews for
what it was that the answer for getting
interviews for wiki election first up to
build an application for all projects
and isn't it always
yeah the common infrastructure how do
you figure out marketing
finance for all of them well that is not
something I can help with but I'm sure
someone else you can help with then
knack looking at that about you Brad did
you have I'm sorry you're having
computer difficulties it's always
frustrating but what is there was there
your ask was there what was it you
wanted help with yeah so basically I'm
trying to open-source some information
on how I can 3d print packaging for my
produce they grow like strawberries
raspberries things like that there's two
main methods that I want to pursue
that's either growing mycelium in a mold
or that's growing help and being able to
use that in some way I know people are
already using kelp for packaging that
you can compost and then put accomplice
back on to like top dress for your
plants I just don't know the actual
technical parts of of that so if anyone
has any suggestions or knows any
resources that would be helpful
I do not know offhand any
that but I think that is also something
that together as humanity we have to
figure out is what material works for
what thing and when someone comes up
with something how do we propagate it
because yes I throw up so much freakin
plastic for my produce and there isn't
any kind of solution for that that works
but I'm guarantee you there's a solution
for that that works that already exists
right now but they and they the people
who have the farms don't know about it
and then the plastic people aren't there
to help them know about it and this is
cheaper and this is more plentiful and
so having a way to correct that with a
system where any because the end
material engineers aren't the people to
be able to market that like they're just
thought and to know that these things
like what you just said probably or
exist that people have used mushroom
mycelium to create it right and so
everyone has to kind of reinvent the
wheel like you've got to figure that out
you've got to figure and then when you
figure it out everyone else has to
figure it out green bug the wheel
because how do you propagate that how
you actually get that up that is in no
way a solution
your problem Brad but an overarching
solution is needed so how much research
have you done on it so far I've done
enough to see that other people are
doing it at big scales that they receive
like a large amount of funding and I
don't know how appropriate is for
someone like me to do that so there are
companies that have that are growing
help at large scales they're currently
using it in their boxes and they have
special help lining so greasy foods and
other things just don't like melt into
the actual packaging but they are like
happening their stuff so I don't I just
don't know how to get what's already in
use to myself so the impure question I
know that it exists I just don't know
the technical part because a lot of that
is proprietary information um you may
have already done this but have you
looked into just like buying like sort
of small orders of the packaging as well
you know somebody who had stuff to ship
might do like you know I'm seeing
containers made out of corn and that
kind of thing like the plastic stuff
that eventually biodegrades the bad
company just bought to offer their stuff
in yeah that's that's my fallback plan I
do have companies in mind have purchased
that where my mind is going though as a
dietician by trade and I always try to
use every opportunity for education
doesn't really make sense to put
strawberries in the standard packaging
of court or whatever it would also be a
great opportunity for me to come up with
my own sort of packaging and maybe group
them in actual fruit serving sizes so
it'll be very intuitive when people buy
strawberries like oh I know what a
serving size of fruit would in relation
to strawberries are but yeah I can use
biodegradable or possible compostable
containers already that are out there so
that's kind of my fallback plan okay
I feel like again not a solution to your
problem
like the supply and demand supply we
need to mad like there are so many
farmers you have the demand side of
things you Kimble the supply side but
it's priced at the point of like this is
new and fun so you want to pay a premium
to have kelp packaging as opposed to no
we all need kelp packaging what scale do
we need to produce it on so it is 10
cents per container and let's create
that like what do we need in place as
opposed to I created it I have a
proprietary solution now it costs $5 to
strawberry bundle to get it there anyway
solutions on a grander scale
let's if we do fine tune this though it
would be a great opportunity for farmers
who can grow their own health and
produce their own packaging and sell
that packaging to other people that are
not farmers that might need packaging
like I need to take out business so it's
a good opportunity again to have
multiple uses at the farm scale even a
small scale so I think this is something
that we as a farming community or even
being the community need to try to solve
do you have all of the expertise as far
as like I guess what pieces of that I'm
wondering if James Jones as a person to
talk to who is doing cube spawn because
I know he is more about like the factory
side of things and not necessarily that
material but he might have had I just
feel like James might have some
solutions as to how to actually make
yeah my Jones with cube spawn that I've
no idea if he be the person to talk to
for it he's just cube spawn it's like a
local manufacturing he's trying to
figure out how to like every block could
have their own manufacturing that is
versatile so whenever you need it to
print and make it moves its pieces and
makes it for you and so he's been
spending his life doing that and
engineering it and putting his effort in
that but I feel like there's something
there up if farmers are able to make
they need a factory and they need he
might just be able to and he's in that
space so he might know just more people
to talk to about yeah I think that's
very helpful
and he's not the person who may know
someone who is so as long as I can get
on a trail and go down the right trail
that I can do a warm introduction after
all message both oh yeah you have to be
friends on Facebook though because
you're disgusting we're talking on
Twitter so I do I know James Johnson
I'll might know on Twitter in which case
I'll figure in a home okay and Brad do
you have a 3d printer I don't have a 3d
printer and it depends on which route we
go if we do like mycelium molds I don't
need one I don't know the technical part
of you know is this gonna get o me or
not homie but a personal 3d printer I
can use Kelvin because the ones that you
buy don't support that material so I
need to figure out what these companies
are using actually I'm not even dressed
possible if they have if it's like
proprietary information and I don't know
how they're really how open they're
gonna be to sharing that with me but I
just need to see like what what it takes
for kelp that would be my ideal thing
I'd rather not use my psyllium but I'll
do recommend so if you do the Cal is
that a 3d printed it's like you I would
imagine it is but it has to be to some
extent but again I need to find out more
information it's just not readily
available the reason I'm asking is I
work for a start-up once that did a 3d
print network so the whole idea was to
network 3d printers so whatever your
project was then you could tap it to
their network and have this printed you
know at scale so yeah depending on what
the financial end of the solution is I
mean I owe you froze
I'll see we'll see if s stable to come
back sexy person talkie is the one who
has the
be a potential just being seeing the
useful like just being able to generate
a kelp base material for 3d printers
would be super cool yeah put it into
anything to make that material so you
could print it into any shape it would
be yes and I do think I hopefully Brad
you can hear us if you can you can't do
the rest but uh listen to our to our
awesome ideas so you don't get to
respond I don't my awesome idea was
probably to awesome about help as a
material just as a material yeah into
that there was there was another layer
that oh oh that the proprietary that was
what I was gonna say a lot of you're
right they might not be willing because
its proprietary also though people who
are here to do good in the world even if
they are forced to do game a make things
patentable are sometimes a lot more open
to yeah and I'll share it with you
because what I want is the kelp made
into plastic so there's less plastic if
they're in it for purpose and not profit
and there'll be someone who's in it for
purpose is a non-profit so if there's
multiple people doing it in multiple
materials somebody's there just to
propagate the idea and they will and
then they get to take over the entire
market cuz there's a you know like if
somebody it's open source and you now
may have material to 3d print and it's
available to everyone and every farmer
can print it we don't need the
proprietary ones you don't need those
look exactly like if then keeping it
proprietary technology forces someone to
go up make an open-source version
they're gonna wish to they're just
license the proprietary version yeah
yeah
and what does licensee look like a 3d
material because if you think like the
thing the filament is the expensive part
of 3d printing right if you have a kelp
version of that that's both the thing
you print is more environmentally
friendly and you can grow your ink like
that solves so much stuff for molds and
stuff you can print a mold and then pour
the stuff in or what I don't know I
don't know but it's cool I like it yeah
and I we've been saying kelp but that's
not to say that it has to be killed for
I'm sure it could be torn or or corn
husks or any kind of
I thought this is what Brad was talking
about when he was talking and I don't
think it actually was he was like I
don't know if I want to put strawberries
in corn and that um corn a lot of people
are allergic to corn and logic to kelp
sorry even the husks are actually eating
Oh
but like it seems like I wouldn't want
that to be done with peanuts
so like corns in everything but it's
also in everything so why not make it
out of it I'm pretty sure most people
file
biology in their bodies is more okay
with corn husks then I mean I have a
different layer of like I want to know
what that process is it turns that into
the corn husk because I want to arch
sorry turns into material because I want
to know if it's actually environmentally
friendly like how much water much energy
what Perot
chemical processes have to happen for
this to be made and the proprietary
nough stall so to keep that secret right
it's like oh very mentally friendly is
it really if you're pouring arsenic into
it or yeah sure that might come the wash
if you're trying to license it you might
know oh I don't want to use this this is
the whole point so I'm just going to
unfortunately Brad it's mentioned in the
not unfortunately unfortunately Brad's
private messaging and I can't
necessarily there we go you know I had a
private message that and so this is the
I really wished regard to make these
links actually clickable but yeah a link
on not just biofuels LG's next wave yeah
companies listed in the article and yes
I would suggest that definitely contact
the ones listed there
I'll go I've not looked at it if there's
a list of nobody he has definitely
contact them yeah there is a company
called Lyle
know lowly where seaweed-based straw
company oh I know I can't figure out how
to take it off of there that was that
actually reminds me of the whole like
paper straw debate that weirded me out
that we went paper when there's so many
like different kinds of biodegradable
plastic and the paper straws are just
terrible so I'm not sure why we tried
like why there is such a hard
which towards paper straws when paper
lobbyists yeah true hemp straws yeah yep
everything
trick-or-treat hemp everywhere except
also I have no idea what the process is
to actually get it into all the things
for eco packaging it's not a shadow
chest I well we were talking typed that
up maybe hemp is a good material go back
Jean yeah yeah and because Brad is near
the coast
seaweed makes sense mmm it's probably
the cheapest to access even more than
corn yeah true you know you can grow
kelp accidentally like you're like oh
there's kelp over there alright that's
right yeah I mean ecosystem needs it see
so that and there's that whole watershed
thing if it grows in the watershed that
we yeah and the strawberries are in the
watershed it's much more you know what
supports the ecosystem of the water it
sounds you know a wide variety of
packaging needs like such come in you
know should probably be able to package
things that are dry and won't last that
long things like that you might just be
you know be able to use for example corn
husks themselves no processing it just
wrap stuff in corn husks in your dock
and then how do we handle wet things or
like a liquid and and that's probably
where I I think Brad mentioned that help
was good for the greasy foods that you
know it doesn't sort of soak through it
like it would with a shallow and I are
just share brain it was like said him
she was typing him and then I was like
we can't take the seaweed out of the
ocean it's same thing at the same time
also both think we have solutions to the
world so I think if you ever can't make
it will just bring in Shiloh if we can't
make it if I can
he's perfect although I think she's
worsen doesn't stumble over as much you
might do better
having yeah there's a few like meta
projects one of which is material like
just knowing where the materials come
from so if you could turn corn into a
material you could 3d print hemp into it
knowing that what those processes are
indeed do-it-yourself like how do you
create this out of here without needing
to get a mold made it and making a
million so it's cheap enough how can you
actually get this down there a lot
there's tons I'm sure if you've already
written this down but it sounds like we
need a solution raising on packaging as
there's a ton there's no other and like
personally I there's been quite a few
things that I haven't bought because the
packaging for is atrocious I'm like all
those cookies look good they're
individually wrapped are you kidding me
nevermind
yeah like oh these are individually
wrapped yeah you know you you you buy
candies and each one has I think around
it like oh my god I don't want this
plastic tool to live on forever because
I wanted a snack like ya know and it is
I racing on packaging is actually pretty
I don't and these are the best ones I
don't know what the solution is for ten
thousand people in a hundred thousand
dollars but there is one key start
generating that there's ones that are
the soft elastic how do we make it the
material and there's also like
restaurant using reusable ones that you
pay a deposit for and get it back but
unless they're all using the same one
that's a whole other maybe not drink
over nineteen but like other and that's
because you do is like pre solutions now
solutions later solutions which there's
a decent chance that like this is the
new norm like not to this extreme but
you know that the the marbling of kovat
nineteen response throughout society
disposable stuff is probably just going
to be more and more and more important
no not at the em you can always shoot he
could always post it on my offers in
needs market mmm see where it goes over
time not anything soon but what would
the what would they need be to know like
the well yeah to try to find that
solution somehow if anybody knows
anybody
who
working in that field or you know might
have some ideas around it mm-hmm and
that's one of the few ones that like
could also be just a game like you could
develop the sort of technology in game B
and licensing appropriately but then
also you know just like make them and
sell them to restaurants you have the
capacity just to generate money itself
to pay for itself to grow like a regular
company which is nice when that becomes
an options notice that you have to but
the fact that I can sort of be
self-sufficient where like a lot of the
projects that we're talking about don't
really have that option to the same
extent as that as yeah I mean if it took
off he gets under the entire part of his
business with that is HUGE I mean being
it anytime I think this is just my input
my hypothesis but anytime you offer to
the world something they can do
themselves they don't actually do it
themselves so offering it to free for
free here's how you could do it yourself
or we're mass producing them that cut
costs plus 5% right and having it
available but it both brings you
marketing and you get innovation because
people can do it themselves right
they're like I tried it this way but
most people don't like even if it's a
super easy cleaner people buy it in a
package rather than make it themselves
right and so I don't think we're such a
but that's the old model of convenience
you have a lot of time on our hair yeah
yeah that's a that's a bottle I mean
that's very much like open source
software you can often give it away and
and then you know do hosting and
enhancements it's a bit challenging what
it does work I mean I haven't dabbled in
that for years I know that but have for
likes hey you know open source but they
still like they sold manuals they sell
implementations and like they got pretty
big yeah and then of course if the
offers in needs market was set up on the
Commons and you had a lot of indigenous
people
on the west coast I would be I would bet
that they would have a solution they've
already figured out how to wrap up stuff
yeah but in some and probably even in
seaweed right yeah and you know that's
part of their culture any indigenous
plant is used in in that culture right
so yeah yeah and that be great to start
incorporating those that wisdom back in
two hours or yeah he might even go to
his the territory that he's on the
nations that live there and asked them
if they had if they have any solution
right that's real good as opposed to
going up into that getting a maybe you
know try the game see or whatever it is
that you know the original indigenous
peoples did on their lands became a yes
I think that's extra cool because then
if it was something that was hopefully
readily available to that tribe or that
community then all of a sudden if we're
talking about possibly like having a as
a business that becomes oh hey if you
can make the packaging then you can sell
it and there's a business for your tribe
sure yeah and then it's like you know
they'll hopefully do it like at a
respectable scale where like it's enough
that they can sell but not too much
where it's like all right pedal down
like you know you're you're kind of
defeating the purpose here on demand so
yeah yeah but then also having an upper
limit right because if it's like sorry
we ran out of that material and there's
no good way to get it talk to us in
three months like and then you know
we'll hopefully have three hundred
tribes head up that way we're like Oh
200 of them are making this fifty or
doing that twenty are doing that here's
the amounts that we have yeah mmm yeah I
mean last night I saw or yesterday I saw
great a mask must be in West Coast may
be Haida out of cedar right so cedar is
sort of interrupt around so you know
this is cedar strips right so it's not
your o'clock bask but it is a mask right
so yeah no new materials that are there
the plus cedar there has been prophecy
from what I've heard about
this pandemic and part of what the first
nations especially on the west coast are
it's cedar cedar your shoot cedar in for
this particular virus it's medicine
happiness Peter mask is like yeah
because it had a stent which has an oil
in it which is also antiviral yeah it's
a lot of a lot of wisdom at the same
time when USA met over the first nations
my first was like but they're not gay
Bay
meaning that they eat like they're
wrapping the berries to eat them for the
next few days during you know for their
tradition they're not mass producing
packaging it so they can send it to a
store so it can be sold but there's
still a wisdom there that might be able
to do both or be able to say eat it with
you wrap it in this and how do we
package these things now want a piece of
the puzzle the solution mm-hmm which I
would prefer to have like personally
suppliers that have that kind of a limit
where they're willing to say like sorry
we we aren't making those now because
you know we ran out of d materials and
it are think that we could do both us
damaging some now although you do have
to think about then what's I mean we're
going to go food yeah you kind of do
need and like our discussions about
resiliency is that you do need kind of
backups in the system so we have a
backup supply of plastic to use and in
those situations or are there three or
four different types of methods like you
have the algae and then you have a
mycelium in that way they you know that
the chance of all three of them going
out at the same time or reaching a max
couldn't happen it's definitely a
complex issue that would be good to work
on yeah ideally you'd want kind of a
fallback like really scalable almost
like you know your 3d printer kelp cook
cartridges where you're like we can
scale that a lot but you know it would
need the need for it but then if we talk
about something that comes from the
First Nations communities that that ends
up being you know wrapping certain
things in corn husks cool then you know
we do that as long as we have corn husks
and when we we run out to the 3d
printers
we're always gonna have corn husks of
anything it's like really not the de
cattle eat corn husks or they just eat
well with climate change though the
prediction is most of the Corn Belt in
America will be destroyed okay
actually we're moving north it'll be
moving up into Canada
so between Alberta and Manitoba
rat-bastard
favorite corn even the corn out here
it's one of the things that Alberta's
got out BC for sure yeah I think Lars
Tabor I don't miss favorite corn that
was good yeah we're over producing corn
and wheat and we're subsidizing it in
the United States which is not very long
term wise I don't have all the details
but that's I also wonder for something
like that how much our farmers like
selling the corn versus just you know
they sell the court and the the husk is
still attached so they're kind of giving
the husk away for free to be able to
throw out yeah yeah if there was a way
to be like hey sell us this we'll pay
you for the court and the husks which is
also having the local production right
like you'd spawn or something where it's
even just the local farmers doing it
that way in something like or shankha if
I'm saying their name right the online
farmers market it like having our supply
change closed so that like okay we have
when I husk my corn at home it doesn't
go into the compost it goes into the I'm
using it to create packaging in my
neighborhood and when I use paper it
doesn't go in and recycle and it goes
into we're making our own toilet paper
locally you know like right there
because and then when you have you don't
have enough paper you can ask other
people you don't have enough corn husks
you can ask other people but it's like a
local commodity of at least we know
we're using ours first and here's where
you collect it I mean again technology
to be able to combine those of like what
are we producing and where does it need
to go and how do we facilitate the
transportation online websites and flow
analysis that could help keep that
efficient that would have been really
impossible 100 years to to manage it
resilient Lee so yeah so Jubilee you
just mentioned making toilet paper out
of paper like is that a real thing like
are you seriously I mean yeah
they that's what you're right so why
wouldn't you I wouldn't you well I mean
that's a great I mean that we should all
start doing that right like if that's
the truth but we need and just like for
the packaging we need a way to turn
paper like we need a little factory
right that turns in it and I guarantee
you that already exists it's just I
don't know where and who created it but
it already exists it's about that person
being spent not being able to sell it
not being able to actually generate in
what a time what a time for it to be
needed right now will be up above teen
Amazon boxes and no toilet paper in our
stores you're painting a picture there
Jubilee using Amazon boxes of toilet
paper even I don't want the logo still
on it too I don't know how deep we want
to get into this discussion but you know
there are other alternatives that have
different pros and cons like bidets and
such yeah yes absolutely agreed and now
that's the one no hard to make yourself
though the day you can buy them online
and attach into an existing toilet yeah
technically even just have like I'm not
sure the terminology things that you you
bought as a kid with like the squirting
flower the actually you have one it's
portable you know you can take it with
you so it is sort of a little bottle
construction with a nozzle right so you
can go anywhere and don't have to fret
about not having your bday know when you
go home from the hospital after giving
birth they give you this like squeeze
bottle that squeezes up it's like a and
I had like three of them for some reason
and I just threw them out pre hope it
don't recycle they were like is it is
here I was like oh my goodness this
would have that's what it could have
been used for Sonny Bay for a whole I
mean never used so I love my kids crowd
you sell them on a different site for
even more
it's the internet their markup ya know
there's always a market market somewhere
which problems are we solving in the
world we all the way this is what
happens when we don't have a hot seat
and someone with a dire need we just
start blatantly actually that's a
problem with having jublee on the call
isn't it yeah always solving follows
it's true without actually solving the
conversation and then left and that we
just kept talking enjoy being part of
the conversation but I can just pop into
all these rooms like you guys saw this
you can stop this run with it oh just do
that every 10 minutes start a new
conversation or somebody wants to go out
with
were there any ass at the beginning of
the call that I missed that people might
want to repeat and the other thing I was
thinking for Brad is maybe if he would
do a share with us a link to a post he
did on social media asking for advice on
this and if we all share that including
LinkedIn because actually I have like
500 people on LinkedIn and so I don't
know which of them might be in the
packaging area or have a second person
in the packaging area so that's that's
maybe one way you can help out see
that's a great idea Bentley mm-hmm so
yeah he's on Twitter so anyone on
Twitter who's friends with me I can
share it and we can all share it and
share chargers so we're gonna where are
we gonna post this information so once
he gets it together like how do we find
this so we can say guess it'd be good to
go ahead and share it enough in the game
be Facebook group okay
because we should all see that so yeah
just create a more post in there with
the link to the Twitter or to their
Facebook post that's public and then
we'll all share the post
yeah I'll share it on mine and say you
know see if anyone has any indigenous
pollutions to that sort of problem are
you very interested to hear that like so
I got longer use like oh we've been
using this for a thousand years okay oh
yeah
yeah I mentioned that reminds me I had
mentioned in one of our other calls I
don't know which one summer sausage
which jubilee and I don't think Adriel
had heard before and that's that's very
similar I mean that's an old-world food
basically because it travels and doesn't
rot doesn't need refrigeration and
there's a similar North American tribe
which begins with the P and I can't
remember the whole word but it's more
berries and we have again yes right
right so I was looking into creating
either my own pemmican or actually
buying it because it feeds it fits my
dietary needs
yeah if you saw some posts saying it
like it's the ultimate survival food
yeah like less which they you know
you're riding a horse for three days you
need something okay yeah I think that's
indigenous to Blackfoot and Cree culture
but not mistaken interesting yeah I
wasn't sure which tribes had our group
said come up with that or discovered it
requests from the beginning a call that
I missed that I could help out with
maybe well you see was talk about the
ask offer sir yes though I'm creating an
offers in needs market and basted
virtually just so it's basically just a
spreadsheet but I've created the page on
the website and I promoting it through
Facebook and Twitter so I was asking if
people could go through that experience
and see if it makes sense right
so I posted the link to my website in
that chat and and if you know of any
other like ways of doing that so that's
just a rapid prototype but like how
would you actually do that in full
full-on tech you know I don't know what
you would how you would do that either I
haven't got one point yeah I'll
definitely take a look at that two
things is adria pedro you were using
what's the tool you were using to
quickly prototype something all right
Mac neck and then I've been using an
affront and designer friend of mine or
using
bubble bubble yeah bubbles I think is
slightly better than neck it makes great
bubble has a better like better
interface options and that has a better
database so you can sort of what your
emphasis is but yeah it would definitely
be I mean yeah although the bubble one
may be sufficient for what you need and
then the interface tweaks might be
better so but yeah but take a look at
SIF have some suggestions and so if you
also I know you posted it in here and I
guess so I'm just about to ask are you
okay Susan if I post it on the comments
and then share it here so everyone can
see it yeah sure Steven also maybe in
the game be space if you have it yeah
now that I know already which everyone
so we're trying to have every week or
every month everyone have like one place
where you put an update video but
anytime anyone wants to share what
they're up to in the game be project
space when it's a game be project as
long as you're not over posting and it's
like you know what update everyday posts
let us know what you're up to so we can
help each other I loved the idea about
sharing Brad's social media posting that
is something we could all be offering
right and maybe we put out a submission
what do you have you want to be shared
and then we vote on which ones and then
we propagate that one right and have one
a week or something like that but
there's a lot of you know we remember a
tree for sure right if you want to send
that to me and I can post in the
Facebook group and from Twitter and I'll
figure figure that out and we have like
one minute left so we can probably
anyone has any wrapped up questions or
comment don't wrap it up with a question
sir leave our audience with a question
or we can just say bye and we will see
you on next Friday is we're having a
conversation about the nap tool right
not Mac itself but about the meta
project conversation the goal is today
I'll actually like put the link and
people can you know going look at the
public version and sign up for a member
account if they
and then with that being active in the
space for a couple of days yeah we can
then actually go through it for people
who haven't had a chance or to go over
any changes that have happened from
feedback over the week and if we have
time I also found a solution for Nick's
proposal of a patio video space so it
doesn't have the scheduling like we
discussed but it does have a thing too
we can see multiple rooms who's in them
and then you can join the video chat for
that room it's a call a call well it's
it's it's Kiko chat qi q och 80 isn't
developed I I know the owner of the
company and actually we can we could
talk about all the details I don't think
it's worth sharing beforehand because I
kind of want to walk you through it but
if we have some time after Adriel is
done well do that so that's gonna be
next Friday at noon and then on Saturday
we're gonna do this again I think we
should do it at least one more time here
on YouTube once we consistently have six
or more people we can move on to zoom or
some other check maybe not technology if
we move to zoom that would be a good
place to do it because it uses zoom in
the background but it has some features
more 8 it for this this share the Kiko
chat does does I meant with assume I
knew is that what you're talking about
oh streaming or not built into the tool
it can support more people because
stringing it only supports six at one
time yeah and we can drop people down I
mean I I personally don't feel I need to
participate in these every Saturday and
we can take baby turns doing that and
like we said moving to also having a
2:00 p.m. slot for people in Australia
but I'd say we'd stay here for a while
to generate until we have consistently
more than 6 people who want to
participate I think that's and we can
generate feel back and forth but when we
have 10 12 going on zoom and breaking
out into groups randomly and by a
project base right like where the
umbrella our projects under like
sense-making or food or cultural or
whatever it happens to be so so that is
what we're doing for Friday and Saturday
next week and we will see you then and
you else have anything to add
we say goodbye all right now you do that
baseball